Nothing ruins a party like the end of the world.
This Is the End is a action, comedy film directed by Evan Goldberg.
While attending a party at James Franco's house, Seth Rogen, Jay Baruchel
and many other celebrities are faced with the apocalypse.
James Franco, played by James Franco.
Jonah Hill, played by Jonah Hill.
Seth Rogen, played by Seth Rogen.
Jay Baruchel, played by Jay Baruchel.
Danny McBride, played by Danny McBride.
Craig Robinson, played by Craig Robinson.
This Is the End is a 2013 American apocalyptic comedy horror film written, directed and
produced by Seth Rogen and Evan Goldberg in their directorial debuts.
It is a feature-length film adaptation of Rogen and Goldberg's 2007 short film Jay and Seth Versus the
Apocalypse, which was directed by Jason Stone, who serves as an executive producer on the film.
Starring James Franco, Jonah Hill, Rogen, Jay Baruchel, Danny McBride, Craig Robinson, Michael Cera and Emma Watson, the
film centers on fictionalized versions of its cast in the wake of a global biblical apocalypse in Los Angeles.
Produced by Mandate Pictures and Rogen and Goldberg's Point Grey Pictures, This Is the End premiered at the Fox Village Theater on June 3, 2013,
before being released theatrically in the United States on June 12, 2013 by Sony Pictures Releasing, via its Columbia Pictures label.
The film received generally positive reviews from critics, who
praised its humor and the six leads' chemistry.
It was also a commercial success, having grossed $127 million
worldwide against a budget of $32–41.9 million.
The film explores themes of friendship, monster, panic, painting, exorcism.
The tone is lighthearted and dark.